The topic of this video is very special to me because it's the slogan of this channel.
这个视频的主题非常特别 因为这是这个频道的口号。
"explore weird machines". So in this video I want to introduce what a weird machine is
"探索奇怪的机器"。所以在这个视频里 我想介绍一下什么是奇怪的机器
and use it to explain return oriented programming. But let's start from a clean slate. Please
并用它来解释面向返回的编程。 但让我们从头开始。拜托
forget the term return oriented programming and weird machine. And let's start with something
忘记术语面向返回编程 还有奇怪的机器。让我们从一些事情开始
else.
否则。
I really want to show you this really weird programming language I made. It's a really
我真的很想让你知道这很奇怪 我做的程序设计语言。这真的是真的
terrible language. But let me show you some example programs.
糟糕的语言。但是我给你看一些 示例程序。
Here is a simple hello world. In this programming language you first have to initialize the
这是一个简单的你好世界。在这个程序中 您首先必须初始化的语言
program, and then you can start writing actual instructions. So here we SET the variable
程序，然后你可以开始写实际的 指令。所以这里我们设置变量
four to the string Hell. And then we store that variable four in memory
四到弦地狱。 然后我们把变量4存储在内存中
location 1. Then we set variable four to O SPACE W O,
位置1。 然后我们把变量4设为空间w o，
and store variable four again in memory location 2. And lastly we set the variable four to
将变量4再次存储在内存位置 2。最后，我们将变量4设置为
rld! and store that value in memory location 3.
RLD！并将该值存储在内存位置 3.
Cool! Next we want to print it. To do that we have
酷！ 接下来我们要打印它。我们已经做到了
to prepare the two parameters for PRINTF. The fist parameter, that will be the destination
为printf准备两个参数。 第一个参数，即目的地
variable, is set to the memory location 1. The memory locations are continuous memory,
变量，设置为内存位置1。 存储器位置是连续存储器，
so printing from location 1 will print the whole string.. And the second parameter of
因此从位置1打印将打印 整个字符串…第二个参数
printf will just be set to 0. It's just a printf of the hello world string. No printf
printf将被设置为0。只是一个 hello world字符串的printf。不打印
format modifiers and parameters here.
这里是格式修改器和参数。
And at the end we exit. All in all a bit ugly language, but makes somewhat sense, right?
最后我们离开。总之有点难看 语言，但有点道理，对吗？
pretty simple. So let's run this program!
很简单。 我们来运行这个程序吧！
First we have to compile it with this python compile script that I wrote. python compile.py
首先我们必须用这个python编译它 编译我写的脚本。python编译.py
helloworld.weird, that's the source code, and the name of the outfile, so helloworld.binary.
很奇怪，这是源代码， 和外文件的名称，所以helloworld.binary。
Let's quickly look at the produced binary in the text editor. It starts off with some
让我们快速看看生成的二进制文件 在文本编辑器中。开始的时候
readable characters, 1, 123 and a lot of AAAAAAAs. But we also can find our Hello world snippets
可读字符，1，123和许多AAAAA。 但我们也可以找到我们的"你好世界"片段
in there. HELL o WO RLD. The other values are just jibberish.
在那里。见鬼去吧。其他价值观 只是在逃避。
But let's run it! To run it you have to simply cat, so print the binary file and pipe the
但让我们开始吧！要运行它，你必须简单地 cat，所以打印二进制文件并通过管道
output into the interpreter, called invoice. Okay, I know the output is really confusing.
输出到解释器中，称为发票。 好吧，我知道输出很混乱。
but that's just part of the weird invoice program. so just ignore that invoicing menu.
但这只是奇怪的发票的一部分 程序。所以忽略开发票菜单。
Because all the way down here at the bottom we can find our output! HELLO WORLD!
因为一直到下面 我们可以找到我们的输出！世界你好！
Awesome!
令人惊叹的！
Let me show you some other examples. This here is a simple ECHO program. It reads a
我再给你举几个例子。这个 这是一个简单的回声程序。它读到
string from standard input into memory location 1. And then also prepares printf with the
从标准输入到内存位置的字符串 1。然后用
memory 1 location to print that string. Again we can try this out by first compiling it,
内存1用于打印该字符串的位置。阿盖恩 我们可以先把它编译一下，
and then we have to output the binary and pipe it into the input of the invoice program.
然后我们必须输出二进制文件， 将其导入到发票程序的输入中。
But not only that, we should also execute cat so the input doesn't close and we can
但不仅如此，我们还应该执行 这样输入就不会关闭，我们可以
send more input that we type to the program. Just some linux commandline foo, don't worry
发送更多我们输入到程序的输入。 只是一些Linux命令行foo，不用担心
about it. but fact is when we execute this, the program waits for input, we can type something
关于它。但事实是，当我们执行这项任务时， 程序等待输入，我们可以输入
in, and the output is here! It worked!!! and please, again ignore the invoice jibberish
在中，输出在这里！它奏效了！！！！和 拜托，还是不要理会发票
menu around it.
菜单在它周围。
Let's do another example. I'm really proud of this one.
让我们再举一个例子。我真的很自豪 这一个。
This will read a string into memory location 1. Then it will execute String to integer
这将把一个字符串读取到内存位置 1。然后它将执行字符串为整数
on that value. So we have to enter a number. The result, so the raw integer number will
在这个价值上。所以我们必须输入一个数字。 结果，所以原始整数
be in the result variable. Then we initialize the variable four with
在结果变量中。 然后我们用
zero, and add the result, so the number we entered to it. Then we store that value into
零，再加上结果，所以我们 进入它。然后我们把这个值存储到
memory location 2.
内存位置2。
Then we read another number as string and convert that string also to an integer. Now
然后我们读另一个数字作为字符串 将该字符串也转换为整数。现在
we load the old value from memory location 2 back into variable four, and then we add
我们从内存位置加载旧值 2回到变量4，然后我们加上
the new converted integer in result to the variable 4.
结果中的新转换整数 变量4。
And then we prepare printf, but this time we have two parameters. The first one is of
然后我们准备打印稿，但这次 我们有两个参数。第一个是
course a format string. The programming language has a few hardcoded format strings like this
设置格式字符串。程序设计语言 有一些这样的硬编码格式字符串
string 1 here. And as the second parameter, we have our variable 4. Cool. Let's try it!!!
这里是字符串1。作为第二个参数， 我们有变量4。酷。让我们试试看！！！！
We compile the sum program. And execute it again with cat. Then we enter the first number.
我们编制了SUM程序。并执行它 又是猫。然后我们输入第一个数字。
Then the second number. And we get the calculated sum output.
然后是第二个号码。我们得到了计算结果 求和输出。
Okay... you ask yourself probably what is up with this weird programming language. Why
可以。。。你可能会问自己什么是 使用这种奇怪的编程语言。为什么？
am I showing this here? Well... the only reason why I showd it was, because I need you to
我在这里展示这个吗？好。。。唯一原因 我展示它的原因是，因为我需要你
fully agree with me, this is a "programming language", right? We can write programs, and
完全同意，这是一个"程序设计" 语言"，对吧？我们可以写程序，而且
then we can somehow compile them, and then they get executed. Simple... but also very
然后我们可以以某种方式编译它们，然后 他们被处决了。简单…而且非常
weird looking.
看起来怪怪的。
So let's have a quick look at the invoice program. It's actually a regular simple c
所以让我们快速看一下发票 程序。它实际上是一个规则的简单C
program. When we just execute it alone we can for example add an invoice, enter an amount
程序。当我们单独执行它的时候 例如，可以添加发票，输入金额
in euro and add a comment. We can add a few more to just get a feeling for the program.
并添加评论。我们可以增加一些 更多的只是为了给程序带来感觉。
And can then select options like calculating the sum of all invoices. Or we can just finalize
然后可以选择计算等选项 所有发票的总和。或者我们可以最后确定
and exit. After entering our name we get a nice list of our invoices.
然后退出。输入我们的名字后，我们得到一个 我们的发票清单很好。
Soooo... wait... what? This is an invoice managment system? So how can this program
Soooo…等待。。。什么？这是发票 管理系统？那么这个程序怎么办
execute these other programs? wat? that doesn't make any sense?
执行这些其他程序？笏？那不 有道理吗？
Let's look again at the binary of one of our compiled programs. We know this is given as
让我们再来看看我们的 编译的程序。我们知道这是作为
input to the invoice program, so let's just try to copy that. And maybe we also run it
输入到发票程序，所以我们只需 试着复制它。也许我们也会经营它
with GDB. So run the invoice program. Then we select 1. Add an invoice. It asks for the
用GDB。所以运行发票程序。然后 我们选择了1个。添加发票。它要求
amount and we enter 123. And then comes all theese AAAAAs... let's copy those and add
我们输入123。然后就来了 这是AAAAA的…让我们复制这些并添加
a bit more data at the end. BOOM! Segmentation fault? RIP, the instruction
最后还有一点数据。 繁荣！分割错误？Rip，指令
pointer is 42424242, so BBBB. We have caused a buffer overflow and overwrote the return
指针是42424242，所以bbbb。我们已经造成 缓冲区溢出并重写返回
pointer on the stack. BAM!
堆栈上的指针。巴姆！
Maybe you think now, ahh... this was just a buffer overflow, and our programs were just
也许你现在认为，啊…这只是 缓冲区溢出，我们的程序
shellcode in assembler. But nope! when you check the security flags you see that the
汇编程序中的shellcode。但是没有！当你 检查安全标志，您会看到
non-executable flag is used. And looking at the memory layout you can also see that the
使用了不可执行的标志。看着 内存布局还可以看到
stack or heap is not executable. So how can we execute these programs even though we can't
堆栈或堆不可执行。所以怎样才能 我们执行这些程序，即使我们不能
inject assembler as shellcode?
将汇编程序作为shellcode注入？
To answer this question I would like Sergey Bratus to introduce the concept of weird machines
为了回答这个问题，我想要谢尔盖 Bratus将介绍奇怪机器的概念
from his talk "What hacker research taught me".
从他所说的"黑客研究所教的 "我"。
Lesson 2, is what I call "composition creates weird machines" parallel universes of computers.
第二课，我所说的"构图创造" 奇怪的机器"计算机的平行宇宙"。
Any complex system turns out to be casting mini shadows. and of these shadows only one
任何复杂的系统都是铸造的 迷你阴影。在这些阴影中只有一个
is what you intended. that is the development environment you work on. everything else is
是你想要的。这就是发展 你工作的环境。其他都是
a weird machine. Whose instructions are actually combinations of your well designed features.
一台奇怪的机器。实际上是谁的指令 您精心设计的功能组合。
But it will run the attackers code. And do exactly what we defined as undermining your
但它会运行攻击者的代码。并且做 正是我们定义的破坏你的
trust assumptions. leading to behaviour that is entirely unexpected by the designer of
信任假设。导致行为 完全出乎意料
the machine.
机器。
So think of stack overflows. Think of heap overflows which are a bit more interesting.
所以想想堆栈溢出。思考堆 更有趣的溢出。
In each case you have a component of your actual machine that is executing instructions
在每种情况下，您都有 正在执行指令的实际计算机
that the exploit crafted input can trigger. That you did not intended to be executed in
利用精心设计的输入可以触发。 你不打算在
that fashion. It's a whole universe of weird machines.
那种时尚。整个宇宙都很奇怪 机器。
So exploitation is from that point of view, programming of that weird machine via crafted
所以剥削是从这个角度来看的， 通过精心设计的程序设计那台奇怪的机器
input most often. And so here is one case study from 1997 when
最常输入。 所以这里有一个1997年的案例研究
a technique called return-into-libc was invented to what the academia now calls return oriented
发明了一种称为回归libc的技术 学术界现在称之为回归导向
programming. And it took about 10 years to propagate.
编程。大约用了10年 传播。
All the work in these series of techniques is done by code fragments already present
这一系列技术中的所有工作 由已经存在的代码片段完成
in the trusted code. So no new untrusted executable code is introduced. No new attacker code is
在可信代码中。因此没有新的不受信任的可执行文件 介绍了代码。没有新的攻击者代码是
introduced. All the manipulation. All the activity is done by parts of the machine that
介绍。所有的操纵。所有的 活动由机器的部件完成
you thought were your friends. Well no, they are traitors, lying and wait.
你以为是你的朋友。嗯，不，他们 都是叛徒，撒谎和等待。
In 2008 when academia finally got a firm understanding of this brand of technique, it was dubbed,
2008年，学术界终于有了一个坚定的理解 这一技术品牌被称为，
malicious computation, to distinguish it from malicious code - which is what your exploit
恶意计算，将其与 恶意代码-这就是您的漏洞所在
(assembly shellcode) is.
（程序集外壳代码）是。
The concept of weird machines is so beautiful and that realization was very impactful to
怪机器的概念太美了 这一认识对
me. Thus it became the mantra ar slogan of my channel.
我。因此，它成了 我的频道。
Return Oriented Programming is one example of using a weird machine. And the weird machine
面向返回的编程就是一个例子 使用一台奇怪的机器。还有奇怪的机器
we have here is implemented in the invoice program. The invoice program implemented one
我们已经在发票上执行了 程序。发票程序执行了一个
intended machine, the invoice management system, but also implemented an endless amount of
预定的机器，发票管理系统， 但也实施了无数的
weird machines due to a stack buffer overflow. The developer has crafted a weird machine
堆栈缓冲区溢出导致的奇怪机器。 开发人员设计了一台奇怪的机器
without even knowing it. A weird machine so powerful that it can execute basically anything.
甚至不知道。一个奇怪的机器所以 功能强大，基本上可以执行任何操作。
So powerful we can create a programming language that only runs on this single weird machine.
如此强大，我们可以创建一种编程语言 只在这台奇怪的机器上运行。
Isn't that amazing? And remember, we do this WITHOUT injecting
这不是很神奇吗？ 记住，我们不注射
arbitrary assembler instructions - we don't have shellcode here. We are using the technique
任意汇编指令-我们不 这里有shellcode。我们正在使用这项技术
of return oriented programming to achieve arbitrary execution. And it's so weird. And
实现面向返回的编程 任意执行。这太奇怪了。和
it's so beautiful at the same time.
同时又很漂亮。
In the next video I want to look closer at the weird programs that I have written, and
在下一个视频中，我想看得更近一些 我写的那些奇怪的程序，还有
what the compiler does, and how exactly this is executed. And if you haven’t already
编译器做什么，以及这到底有多精确 执行。如果你还没有
guessed it, let me give you a small teaser, you could call these “instructions” actually
猜对了，让我给你个小笑话， 实际上，你可以称之为"说明"。
“gadgets” *wink* *wink*. So next video we will learn how return oriented programming
"小工具"*传情动漫**传情动漫*。所以下一个视频 我们将学习如何面向返回编程
works.
作品。
But in the meantime, please go watch the talks I have linked below and read the papers I
但与此同时，请去看会谈 我在下面链接并阅读了我的论文
have linked. For me, they belong to the most important computer science and hacking or
有联系。对我来说，它们属于最 重要的计算机科学和黑客或
IT security papers.
IT安全文件。
https://www.cs.dartmouth.edu/~sergey/hc/rss-hacker-research.pdf
网址：https://www.cs.dartmouth.edu/~sergey/hc/rss-hacker-research.pdf